Episode 3
에피소드 3
Kediaman Hua
케디아만 후아
hungry?
배고픈?
Sir, Mr. Chong has arrived.
선생님, 종 씨가 도착했습니다.
good.
좋은.
- teacher. - sorry.
- 선생님. - 미안해요.
I was late because I was busy.
바빠서 늦었어요.
are you okay. Work is more important.
괜찮아. 일이 더 중요합니다.
sit down.
앉아.
Yes, let's sit down.
응, 앉자.
Because it's late...
늦었으니까...
As punishment, you must drink a glass of wine.
벌로 포도주 한 잔을 마셔야 합니다 .
Well, I'll pour you a full glass.
글쎄, 한 잔 가득 부어줄게 .
This is an aged wine bottle.
숙성된 와인병 입니다..
We haven't started eating yet.
우리는 아직 식사를 시작하지 않았습니다.
Don't drink the wine first.
와인을 먼저 마시지 마세요.
approval.
승인.
You must be hungry.
배가 고프겠군요.
Eat first.
먼저 먹어라.
Yeah, eat something.
응, 뭐 좀 먹어.
great. let's eat.
좋아요. 먹자.
- Yes, let's eat. - Okay, let's eat.
- 응, 먹자. - 알았어, 먹자.
Do you like this food?
이 음식을 좋아하시나요?
Very good.
아주 좋아요.
no.
아니.
Please congratulate my sister-in-law.
제 처제를 축하해 주세요 .
Drink up, daughter-in-law. This is a good wine.
마셔요, 며느리님. 이것은 좋은 와인입니다.
My father kept it.
아버지가 보관하셨습니다.
I drink first.
내가 먼저 마신다.
how?
어떻게?
let's eat.
먹자.
one more.
하나 더.
I'm saving this for special occasions.
나는 특별한 경우를 위해 이것을 저장합니다.
Eat, honey.
먹어라, 얘야.
Go ahead and try it. older brother.
어서 해봐요. 형님.
Congratulations again.
다시 한번 축하드립니다.
From the comfort of your own home.
집에서 편안하게.
- Eat it. - great.
- 그것을 먹을. - 좋아요.
let's eat. Eat again.
먹자. 다시 먹어라.
Try this.
이 시도.
Go ahead and try it.
어서 해봐요.
Congratulations again .
다시 한 번 축하드립니다 .
For the first time...
처음으로...
I met you...
난 당신을 만나고...
I think you and my sister...
내 생각엔 너랑 내 여동생이...
A matching couple.
어울리는 커플.
Now, drink it.
자, 마셔보세요.
Make it like your own home.
자신의 집처럼 만들어보세요.
We are family now.
우리는 이제 가족입니다.
Agree? me...
동의하다? 나...
My sister found the perfect person.
내 여동생이 딱 맞는 사람을 찾았어요.
You must treat that person well.
당신은 그 사람을 잘 대접해야 합니다.
Well, one more drink. Congratulations again.
음, 한 잔 더. 다시 한번 축하드립니다.
Brother...
동생...
Please help us succeed.
당신이 성공할 수 있도록 도와주세요.
As Madame Kediaman Zhong...
마담 케디아만 종(Kediaman Zhong)으로서...
You will meet many women in the future.
너는 앞으로 많은 여자를 만날 것이다 .
Find a good girl for your brother.
동생에게 좋은 여자를 찾아보세요 .
- Did you hear? - Go ahead and try it.
- 들었어? - 어서 해봐요.
My brother is 23 years old...
형은 23살인데..
And I need to get married quickly.
그리고 빨리 결혼해야 해.
Of course, there are many concubines, but...
물론 첩도 많지만...
Who lives in that person's house?
그 사람 집에는 누가 살고 있지?
I heard that he bought a lot of maids .
그 사람이 하녀를 많이 샀다고 들었어 .
If you are legally married...
법적으로 결혼했다면..
There won't be room for them all.
그들 모두를 위한 공간은 없을 것입니다 .
You can't say that.
그렇게 말할 수는 없습니다.
Every man has several concubines.
모든 남자에게는 여러 명의 첩이 있습니다.
However, a legitimate first wife is essential.
하지만 합법적인 첫 부인은 필수입니다.
yes?
예?
Why couldn't Mom find it for Dad?
왜 엄마는 아빠를 위해 그것을 찾지 못했습니까?
Don't be stupid.
바보같은 소리 하지 마세요.
Kian.
키안.
What did you say?
뭐라고 하셨나요?
naught.
아무것도 아님.
Eat it.
그것을 먹을.
older brother.
형님.
We became a family.
우리는 가족이 되었습니다.
Listen, do you have enough maids?
들어보세요, 하녀가 충분 합니까?
If not, you can tell me.
그렇지 않다면 나에게 말해도 됩니다.
I just bought a lot of pretty maids.
방금 예쁜 하녀들을 많이 샀어요 .
If you like it, we'll send it to you.
마음에 드시면 보내드리겠습니다.
Huang, Shen is drunk.
황, 쉔은 취했어요.
Take him to his room.
그를 그의 방으로 데려가세요.
- Be nice to your sister. - All right.
- 누나한테 잘 대해줘. - 알겠습니다.
Did you understand? me...
이해하셨나요? 나...
Teacher, please go.
선생님, 가세요.
go away. I can barely speak...
저리 가요. 말을 거의 못해요...
With my sister.
내 여동생과 함께.
let's go.
가자.
Please set him free.
그분을 석방시켜 주시 ​​오.
Take the cane I use for physical training.
내가 신체적 훈련을 위해 사용하는 지팡이를 가져가세요 .
rattan...
등나무...
Sorry, I'm a little drunk.
죄송해요, 제가 좀 취했어요.
Let me ask myself first.
먼저 나 자신에게 물어보겠습니다.
- We... - Dad.
- 우리... - 아빠.
late. We go first.
늦었 어. 우리가 먼저 간다.
See you later.
또 보자.
Always visit us.
항상 우리를 방문하십시오.
Go home safely.
집에 조심히 가세요.
It's all your fault.
모든게 다 너의 잘못이야.
Why mention wisteria?
왜 등나무를 언급합니까?
You ruined the food.
당신은 음식을 망쳤습니다.
I haven't talked to him yet.
나는 아직 그와 얘기하지 않았습니다.
I haven't had a drink yet.
나는 아직 술을 마시지 않았습니다.
Drink it.
마셔보세요.
You drink alone.
당신은 혼자 술을 마신다.
Why did you come back in such a hurry today?
오늘은 왜 이렇게 서둘러 돌아왔나요 ?
Don't you want me to talk to your father?
내가 네 아버지와 얘기하는 걸 원하지 않니 ?
He was just talking...
그 사람은 그냥 얘기하고 있었어...
About work issues.
업무 문제에 대해.
Even though they are both married...
둘다 결혼했는데도..
We should not mix work and family .
우리는 일과 가족을 섞어서는 안 됩니다 .
Thank you for your consideration.
당신의 배려에 감사합니다.
If only my father could...
아버지께서 하실 수만 있다면...
Stop thinking About maintaining a relationship...
생각을 멈추세요 관계 유지에 대해...
That will make my job easier
그렇게 하면 내 일이 더 쉬워질 것입니다.
Appears to be painful to the eyes In the Zhong family...
눈에 고통을 주는 것으로 보임 종 가문에서는...
Make my life difficult
내 인생을 어렵게 만드세요.
Father's power I can no longer deny it.
아버지의 능력 더 이상 거부할 수 없습니다.
Because he agreed To Mu Yunping's opinion...
그가 동의했기 때문에 무윤핑의 의견에...
I have to...
해야죠...
I miss you Muyao
무야오 보고싶다
Sir, the guard said...
선생님, 경비원이 말했어요...
Mr. Mu ran away.
뮤 씨가 도망쳤어요.
If you have to go, you have to go.
꼭 가야 한다면 가야 해요.
I can go alone.
나 혼자 갈 수 있어요.
We'll be waiting for you at Hua Residence.
Hua Residence에서 기다리겠습니다.
sorry.
죄송합니다.
Penjara
펜자라
Wait a minute.
잠깐 기다려요.
What are you all doing?
다들 뭐하고 계시나요?
Sir, I'm on my way...
선생님, 지금 가는 중입니다...
To find my family.
가족을 찾으러.
- How can I help you? - progress.
- 어떻게 도와 드릴까요? - 진행하다.
I need to talk to the guard.
경비병한테 얘기 좀 해야겠어요
All right.
알겠습니다.
follow me.
날 따라와.
what?
무엇?
Do you want to share a prison with your father?
아버지와 감옥을 공유하고 싶나요 ?
How many...
몇 명...
Who do you want to fool with this look?
이 표정으로 누구를 속이고 싶나요 ?
My father is innocent.
나의 아버지는 결백합니다.
So I will find the truth.
그래서 나는 진실을 찾을 것입니다.
Many people won't believe you.
많은 사람들이 당신을 믿지 않을 것입니다.
do you trust me
당신은 날 믿어?
Are you on your way to your in-laws?
시댁으로 가는 길인가요 ?
This is not the place to talk.
이곳은 얘기할 곳이 아닙니다.
why? Can't you see him?
왜? 그 사람을 볼 수 없나요?
It's not like that.
그렇지 않습니다.
Mu Yao and I are like brothers.
무야오와 나는 형제 같아요.
He's in trouble now.
그는 지금 곤경에 빠졌습니다.
So I am very worried.
그래서 나는 매우 걱정됩니다.
So I would like to meet him.
그래서 나는 그를 만나고 싶습니다.
Do you know everything?
당신은 모든 것을 알고 있나요?
Qian, trust me.
퀴안, 날 믿어.
I only do this because that person is an acquaintance of mine.
그 사람이 내 지인이기 때문에 그렇게 하는 것뿐입니다 .
You don't need to explain it to me.
나에게 설명할 필요는 없습니다 .
I know you and Mu Yao are close...
나는 당신과 Mu Yao가 친한 것을 알고 있습니다 ...
And he was a good friend.
그리고 좋은 친구였죠.
I just want to talk to him.
나는 단지 그와 이야기하고 싶습니다.
I don't want to ask you.
나는 당신에게 묻고 싶지 않습니다.
great.
좋아요.
Qian, we did it as a friend.
Qian, 친구로서 했어요 .
When you were awake at the funeral with me...
당신이 나와 함께 장례식에 깨어 있었을 때 ...
I vow to love only you in this life.
나는 이생에서 당신만을 사랑할 것을 맹세합니다 .
Thank you for your confirmation.
확신해 주셔서 감사합니다.
But it wasn't me who swore.
하지만 맹세한 것은 제가 아니었습니다.
Kalau betul pun...
Kalau betul pun...
It won't stop you...
그것은 당신을 멈추지 않을 것입니다...
Falling in love with him
그와 사랑에 빠지는 것
The person blocking the way is me.
길을 가로막는 사람은 바로 나입니다.
After talking with Qian today...
오늘 Qian과 얘기를 나눈 후 ...
I have noticed that he is more mature now.
나는 그가 이제 더 성숙해졌다는 것을 알아차렸다.
Then you will feel at ease.
그러면 마음이 편해집니다.
That's right, that person has changed a lot.
그렇죠, 그 사람 많이 변했어요.
He used to call me spoiled.
그는 나를 버릇 없다고 부르곤 했어요.
Now he's grown up too...
이제 그 사람도 컸어...
And call me formally.
그리고 나한테 정식으로 전화해.
Think of it this way.
이렇게 생각해보세요.
One day...
어느 날...
That person will be your wife.
그 사람은 부인이 될 거예요
So it's good to mature quickly.
그래서 빨리 성숙해지는 것도 좋아요 .
It's been 3 days since he got married...
그 사람 결혼한지 3일됐는데..
And he is too formal for me.
그리고 그는 나에게 너무 형식적입니다 .
That person is also depressed...
그 사람도 우울증인데..
Talking to me today.
오늘 나랑 얘기하면서 .
I don't think I know him.
나는 그를 모르는 것 같습니다.
He is like a stranger.
그는 낯선 사람과 같습니다.
I don't believe it.
나는 그것을 믿지 않는다.
That person always acts...
그 사람은 항상 행동하는데...
in front of you
당신의 앞에
How can you do that?
어떻게 그럴수있어?
Of course you are wrong.
물론 당신은 틀렸어요.
It's an old story.
그것은 오래된 이야기입니다.
Just forget it.
그냥 잊어 버리세요.
He is now married into another family.
그는 현재 다른 가족과 결혼했습니다.
That means...
그 뜻은...
We don't have to worry...
우리는 걱정할 필요가 없습니다 ...
Again about our children.
다시 우리 아이들에 대해.
great.
좋아요.
Sensei should get married
센세는 결혼해야지
At this age.
이 나이에.
sulfur.
황.
Where do you want to sneak away?
어디로 몰래 빠져나가고 싶나요 ?
Come this way.
이리 오세요.
Tuan, Tuan Hua...
투안, 투안화...
What did he do?
그는 무엇을 했나요?
Please let me know.
알려줘요.
Tuan.
투안.
He said he couldn't sleep after drinking.
술을 마시고 잠을 못 잔다고 하더군요 .
So he asked...
그래서 그가 물었다...
I brought a woman from Baekhwagung...
백화궁에서 여자를 데려왔는데 ..
For his friend.
그의 친구를 위해.
No need to bother.
귀찮게 할 필요가 없습니다.
Bring me the Staff of Discipline.
나에게 규율의 지팡이를 가져다주세요.
don't do it
하지 않다.
to.
에게.
He drank to become a good master of the bell.
그는 종 경의 좋은 주인이 되기 위해 술을 마셨다.
Maybe he drank too much.
어쩌면 그는 너무 많이 마셨을 수도 있습니다.
late.
늦었 어.
Just forget it.
그냥 잊어 버리세요.
I'll bring it myself.
내가 직접 가져오도록 할게요.
You are spoiling him too much.
당신은 그를 너무 많이 망치고 있습니다.
to.
에게.
you...
너...
Get ready for tomorrow.
내일 준비하세요.
to.
에게.
I want to be safe this time.
이번에는 안전하고 싶습니다.
There is no need to suffer...
고생할 필요는 없어요...
To achieve peace.
평화를 이루기 위해.
If you kill someone...
사람을 죽이면...
You threatened my life...
내 생명을 위협했어요...
There is no need for that...
그럴 필요는 없어요...
Why are you with me?
왜 나와 함께 있나요?
My previous deaths Wasn't it bad enough
나의 이전 죽음 충분히 나쁘지 않았나요?
How could I think like that?
내가 어떻게 그런 생각을 할 수 있지?
If the person is innocent You must accept the plea...
그 사람이 결백한 경우 답변을 받아들여야 합니다...
For my safety...
내 안전을 위해...
I am just repeating history.
나는 역사를 반복하고 있을 뿐입니다.
Hua Chen, wake up...
화첸, 일어나...
You are awake.
당신은 깨어있습니다.
I heard you were here.
당신이 여기 있었다고 들었습니다.
So I came to see you.
그래서 당신을 만나러 왔습니다.
why?
왜?
So can I brag about my victory?
그럼 승리를 자랑해도 될까요 ?
That is my intention...
그게 바로 내 의도입니다...
When I did this before
전에 이 일을 했을 때
Hua Qian, listen.
Hua Qian, 들어보세요.
Even if you deny your actions ...
자신의 행동을 부정하더라도 ...
Sometime later...
나중에 언젠가...
I will expose your cruelty to the world...
너의 잔인함을 세상에 폭로하겠다 ...
And the hypocrisy of your family.
그리고 당신 가족의 위선.
Do evil and repay evil.
악을 행하고 악을 갚으십시오.
Your family will not live in peace.
당신의 가족은 평화롭게 살지 못할 것입니다.
I don't want to talk about the past.
나는 과거에 대해 이야기하고 싶지 않습니다 .
But now I can guarantee...
하지만 지금은 보장할 수 있어요...
Your family can't do anything.
당신의 가족은 아무것도 할 수 없습니다.
What game are you playing now?
지금 무슨 게임을 하고 있나요?
Please let me know.
알려줘요.
You pretend it's my place to complain.
당신은 내가 불평할 곳인 척해요.
What else...
또 뭐...
Can you write to me ?
나 한테서 쓸 수 있는 거요 ?
I don't want to use you for anything .
나는 당신을 어떤 용도로든 이용하고 싶지 않습니다 .
Do you still think you can fool me?
아직도 나를 속일 수 있을 것 같아 ?
What have I been going through in the past few days...
지난 며칠간 나는 무슨 일을 겪었는지 ...
Just showing who you really are is enough.
당신의 진정한 모습을 보여주는 것만으로도 충분합니다 .
Pretending to be weak...
약한 척...
But your heart is evil.
그러나 네 마음은 악하다.
From the beginning...
처음부터...
You know what you want from me
나한테 뭘 원하는지 알잖아
How much.
얼마나 많이.
Did you see the parrot earlier?
아까 앵무새 보셨나요 ?
Is that a parrot?
저거 앵무새야?
Did you see it?
당신은 그것을 볼 않았다?
I accidentally scared him.
나는 우연히 그에게 겁을 주었다.
Let us help you find it.
당신이 그것을 찾을 수 있도록 도와 드리겠습니다.
You are good.
당신은 좋습니다.
you're welcome.
천만에요.
Who is he?
그는 누구입니까?
How dare he make fun of Mr. Zhong?
그가 감히 종 씨를 놀리나요?
Okay, Sister Hua.
좋아요, 화 자매님.
I know you won't believe me...
내 말을 당신이 믿지 않을 거라는 걸 알아요 ...
About the past.
과거에 대해.
But I have no intention of hurting you now .
하지만 지금은 당신에게 상처를 줄 생각이 없습니다.
Now you want me to trust you?
이제 내가 당신을 믿어주기를 바라나요 ?
Hua Qian, your assistant sent you...
Hua Qian, 당신의 조수가 보냈습니다 ...
The furniture is filled with agarwood...
가구는 침향으로 가득 차 있습니다 ...
To my house.
우리 집으로.
Now my family is being punished...
이제 우리 가족은 처벌을 받습니다...
For embezzling money.
돈을 횡령했다는 이유로.
I have talked to you many times.
나는 당신과 여러 번 이야기했습니다 .
Not only does it deny everything...
모든 것을 부정할 뿐만 아니라...
You too, report me to the authorities.
당신도 당국에 나를 신고합니다.
Now what?
이제 뭐?
Are you trying to change your story?
당신은 당신의 이야기를 바꾸려고 노력하고 있습니까?
Try to remain calm.
침착함을 유지하도록 노력하세요.
Muyao, a lot has happened…
무야오, 많은 일이 있었어…
It's out of our control...
우리 통제 밖이야...
It doesn't match my current mental state.
내 현재 정신 상태 와 일치하지 않습니다 .
You can't change everything at once .
한 번에 모든 것을 바꿀 수는 없습니다 .
So I can only do it little by little.
그래서 조금씩만 할 수 있어요 .
I understand why you don't trust me.
당신이 왜 나를 신뢰하지 않는지 이해합니다 .
But I promise...
하지만 약속해요...
Everything I say from now on is true.
지금부터 내가 말하는 것은 모두 사실이다.
Don't do anything stupid anymore.
더 이상 바보 같은 짓을 하지 마세요.
My father was deported...
아버지가 추방당했어요..
And I'm a wanted criminal.
그리고 나는 수배범이야.
Why should I trust you?
내가 왜 당신을 믿어야합니까?
I heard something falling.
뭔가 떨어지는 소리가 들렸어요.
your face...
너의 얼굴...
face?
얼굴?
Did he hit you?
그 사람이 당신을 때렸어요?
no.
아니요.
I am good enough to accept you.
나는 당신을 받아들일 만큼 충분히 좋습니다.
How dare you hurt Qian?
어떻게 감히 Qian을 다치게 합니까?
You made a mistake.
당신은 실수를 했습니다.
This has nothing to do with him.
이것은 그와 아무 관련이 없습니다.
I know you are good.
나는 당신이 좋은 것을 알고 있습니다.
You don't have to advocate for him.
당신은 그를 위해 변호할 필요가 없습니다.
I don't think I should help you...
내가 도와주면 안 될 것 같은데....
I made it myself.
내가 직접 만들었어요.
that's right.
맞아요.
There's a bug on my face
얼굴에 벌레가 생겼어요
Qian, you don’t have to be that good.
퀴안, 그렇게 잘할 필요는 없어.
Sir, don't think too much.
선생님, 너무 많이 생각하지 마세요.
Mu Yao didn't hurt me.
Mu Yao는 나를 해치지 않았습니다.
Imagine yourself in his shoes.
자신이 그의 입장에 있다고 상상해보세요.
Women are most afraid of being sexually harassed.
여자들은 성추행당하는 것을 가장 두려워한다.
So you should apologize to that person.
그러니 그 사람에게 사과해야 해요.
By uniting them...
그들을 통합함으로써...
I I hope this eliminates the hatred...
저는 이것이 증오심을 없애기를 바랍니다...
I triggered Until they parted
내가 촉발한 그들이 헤어질 때까지
Do you think...
당신 생각엔...
I am a wild woman...
난 야만적인 여자야...
And is it unreasonable?
그리고 불합리한데?
Anyway it doesn't matter.
어쨌든 그것은 중요하지 않습니다.
I go first.
내가 먼저 간다.
Where are you going?
어디 가세요?
Want to break into a prison?
감옥에 침입하고 싶나요?
It's better than just sitting still.
그냥 가만히 앉아 있는 것보다 낫습니다.
Being kicked out of the country is like a death sentence.
국외로 쫓겨나는 것은 사형선고와 같습니다.
How do you want to see your father die?
아버지가 죽는 걸 어떻게 보고 싶나요 ?
I took a risk...
나는 위험을 무릅썼다...
To help you...
당신을 돕기 위해 ...
Because you are friends with Qian.
당신은 Qian과 친구이기 때문입니다.
You can't do that now .
지금은 그렇게 할 수 없습니다 .
I never asked you to save me...
구해달라고 한 적 없는데 ...
Or help him escape from prison.
아니면 감옥에서 탈출할 수 있게 도와주세요.
now...
지금...
I just hope you aren't busy.
나는 단지 당신이 바쁘지 않기를 바랍니다.
Do you think that way about me too ?
당신도 나에 대해 그렇게 생각하나요 ?
If I don't help you, you'll already...
내가 도와주지 않으면 넌 이미...
Are you sure it's from Jiaozhi?
Jiaozhi에서 온 것이 확실합니까?
yes. Most of them are agarwood...
예. 대부분이 아가우드인데...
Shipped from Qiongzhou.
Qiongzhou에서 배송됩니다.
It is difficult to get much from Jiaozhi .
Jiaozhi로부터 많은 것을 얻는 것은 어렵습니다 .
Come with me to Bell Park.
나와 함께 종 공원으로 가세요.
Assistant Hua, what do you mean?
Hua 조수님, 무슨 뜻인가요?
Sir, your boss is not embezzling money.
선생님, 당신의 상사는 돈을 횡령하지 않습니다.
Look at.
바라보다.
This agarwood...
이 침향나무...
It's from our workshop.
우리 작업장에서 왔어요.
The staff may have changed.
직원이 바뀌었을 수도 있습니다.
Whereby...
그로 인해...
He used the wrong type...
그는 잘못된 유형을 사용했습니다 ...
To make agarwood balls.
침향 공을 만들기 위해.
Do you believe this?
당신은 이 말을 믿습니까?
There is a possibility that he is unskilled...
미숙련자일 가능성도 있고 ..
Importing incorrect data.
잘못된 자료를 가져옵니다.
Isn't it next to the agarwood...
아가우드 옆에 있지 않나요 ...
At the director’s house?
감독님 집에서요?
But teacher...
그런데 선생님...
Maybe something from his own collection...
아마도 자신의 컬렉션에서 나온 것일 수도 있습니다 ...
This is the material we use.
이것이 우리가 사용하는 재료입니다 .
Please look carefully.
주의 깊게 살펴보시기 바랍니다.
This was sent from the church branch, right?
이거 교지국에서 보낸 거 맞죠?
The smell is different...
냄새가 달라요..
than what was obtained in Qiongzhou .
Qiongzhou에서 얻은 것보다 .
Isn't it raw material...
원자재 아닌가...
That person manages...
그 사람이 관리하는...
Is it produced in Qiongzhou?
Qiongzhou에서 생산됩니까?
of.
의.
actually...
실제로...
what's the matter?
무슨 일이야?
Tuan.
투안.
Teacher, let me tell you this...
선생님, 이것만 말씀드리자면...
As a neighbor of Agarwood...
아가우드 이웃으로서...
It is managed by a supervisor.
감독관이 관리하는 것입니다.
I have been working with him for a year.
나는 그와 1년 동안 함께 일해 왔습니다 .
We work well together.
우리는 함께 잘 일해요.
at last...
결국...
He's been working here a long time...
그 사람은 여기서 오랫동안 일해왔어...
And manage our business from the North...
그리고 북쪽에서 우리 사업을 관리해 보세요...
well.
잘.
He deserves credit for that.
그는 그 점에 대해 공로를 인정받을 자격이 있습니다.
Even if that person did something wrong...
그 사람이 잘못했어도..
Missing data found.
누락된 자료를 찾았습니다 .
Expulsion is like a death sentence.
추방은 사형 선고와 같습니다.
Please excuse me...
변명해주시길 바랍니다...
Magistrate Don to reduce his sentence.
그의 형량을 줄이기 위해 돈 치안 판사에게 .
Tuan.
투안.
The same goes for people who swear...
욕하는 사람들도 마찬가지고...
Regarding the embezzlement case...
금품횡령 사건에 대해서..
Now with your own money...
이제 자기 돈으로..
To defend Mu Yanping.
Mu Yanping을 방어하기 위해.
It seems like he's involved in everything ...
그 사람이 모든 일에 관여하고 있는 것 같은데 ...
Including the Zhong family matter.
Zhong 가족 문제를 포함하여.
Get out.
나가세요.
ma'am.
부인.
yes?
예?
Did you hear clearly ?
확실히 들으셨나요 ?
Are you really Deacon Wang?
왕 집사님 맞나요...
Reduce the banishment penalty...
추방형을 줄여라...
3 years for Mu Yunping?
무윤핑에게 3년?
What I heard is true.
내가 들은 것은 사실이다.
You want to forgive that person...
당신은 그 사람을 용서하고 싶은데요...
Because of their contribution to the family.
가족에 대한 기여 때문입니다 .
So he makes excuses...
그래서 그는 변명한다...
To the magistrate Don to mitigate the punishment.
처벌을 완화하기 위해 돈 치안 판사에게 .
now...
지금...
Everyone praises his goodness.
모두가 그의 선하심을 찬양합니다.
I was deported abroad for 3 years.
3년 동안 국외로 추방되었습니다.
Mu Yunping could not commit suicide...
무윤핑은 자살할 수 없었습니다...
Because of despair
절망감 때문에
Your future is bright
당신의 미래는 밝습니다
Jaga Diri
자가 디리
Wear your hood...
후드를 쓰세요...
Sometimes you pay money to someone on the street...
길거리에서 누군가에게 돈을 지불하기도 하고...
I want to send this letter to Mu Yunping.
무윤핑에게 이 편지를 보내려고요 .
Don't tell anyone who you are.
당신이 누구인지 아무에게도 알리지 마십시오 .
This is very important.
이건 매우 중요합니다.
So don't ask any more questions.
그러니 더 이상 질문하지 마세요.
Remember this when it comes out...
이거 나오면 기억해두세요...
end me
나를 끝내다
Madam, I swear on my life.
부인, 제 목숨을 걸고 맹세합니다.
why?
왜?
naught.
아무것도 아님.
She is a housekeeper.
그녀는 가정부입니다.
I guess I'll have to find it...
찾아야 할 것 같네요...
A more capable person
더 유능한 사람
ma'am.
부인.
Kenapa dengan Qianzhi?
Kenapa dengan Qianzhi?
naught. He's too young...
아무것도 아님. 그 사람은 너무 어려요...
You will face something serious.
심각한 일에 직면하게 됩니다.
Look at the ledger.
장부를 보세요.
Please leave it here.
여기에 남겨주세요.
I haven't seen you for several days.
나는 며칠 동안 당신을 보지 못했습니다 .
You are thin.
당신은 말랐습니다.
nurse...
유모...
Thank you God for your mercy...
자비를 베푸신 하나님께 감사드립니다 ...
So the father survived.
그래서 그 아버지는 살아 남았습니다.
Even though it is a barren land...
척박한 땅인데도..
Three years will pass quickly .
3년은 금방 지나갈 것이다 .
Dad can handle it.
아빠가 감당할 수 있어요.
I've organized a few things.
몇 가지를 정리했습니다.
You shouldn't be too harsh on your father .
아버지를 너무 가혹하게 대하면 안 됩니다.
I wrote to your uncle and aunt in the north.
나는 북쪽에 있는 당신의 삼촌과 이모에게 편지를 썼습니다 .
You can stay with that person...
당신은 그 사람과 함께있을 수 있습니다 ...
For three years...
삼 년간...
Until dad comes back...
아빠가 돌아오실 때까지...
To find you.
당신을 찾으려고.
My father's life was saved, but...
아버지의 목숨은 구했지만..
Our castle is still desecrated...
우리 성은 아직도 더럽혀져 있는데...
And dad is still there...
그리고 아빠는 아직 거기 계시고...
Money laundering penalties.
자금세탁 처벌.
I want to live here...
나는 여기서 살고 싶다...
To investigate the truth...
진실을 조사하기 위해..
And please restore our family’s honor.
그리고 우리 가문의 명예를 회복시켜 주십시오.
Unable to.
할 수 없습니다.
You are just a woman.
당신은 단지 여자입니다.
How would you change this case?
이 케이스를 어떻게 변경하시겠습니까?
I am thankful...
나는 감사하다...
Something you are not involved in.
당신이 관여하지 않은 것.
You always say...
당신은 항상 말하죠...
I grew up in the north...
난 북쪽에서 자랐어...
And I am a wild boy.
그리고 나는 야생 소년입니다.
I am not like other women.
나는 다른 여자와는 다릅니다.
So don't ignore me...
그러니 나를 무시하지 마세요 ...
As a woman.
여자로서.
don't worry.
걱정 하지마.
I will reveal the truth...
진실을 밝히겠습니다..
Please restore our family's honor.
우리 가문의 명예를 회복시켜 주십시오 .
Then I will take my father to the city.
그러면 나는 아버지를 도시로 데려갈 것이다.
Thank you for your service Jongho...
종호님의 서비스에 감사드립니다...
And he allowed me to see my father again.
그리고 아버지를 다시 볼 수 있게 허락해 주셨어요 .
I can return the favor, sir...
은혜를 갚을 수 있겠네요 선생님...
While working as a housekeeper...
가정부로 일하면서 ..
for your family
당신의 가족을 위해
not needed.
필요 없음.
I have to return the favor, sir.
은혜를 갚아야겠습니다 선생님.
I said there was no need.
나는 필요 없다고 말했다.
We have no shortage of workers.
우리에게는 일꾼이 부족하지 않습니다.
After all, we are friends.
결국, 우리는 친구입니다.
We always fought...
우리는 항상 싸웠어요...
but i respect you
하지만 난 당신을 존경해요
How are you.
잘 지내세요.
If you don't want to take my offer...
내 제안을 받아들이고 싶지 않다면 ...
I'm afraid the secret will be leaked...
비밀이 누설될까봐 ...
When I'm free
내가 한가할 때
because of you...
당신 때문에...
I was able to avoid getting caught...
잡히지 않게 할 수 있었는데 ..
While my family was on the run.
우리 가족이 도망치는 동안.
Are you threatening me?
나를 협박하는 겁니까?
no.
아니요.
That wasn't my intention.
그건 내 의도가 아니었어.
I just hope you do...
난 그냥 네가 그러길 바랄 뿐이야...
Please allow me to repay you.
내가 당신에게 갚을 수 있게 해주세요.
Do you repay my kindness?
내 친절에 보답해?
How does that work?
그게 어떻게 되나요?
You have a right to be angry.
당신은 화를 낼 권리가 있습니다.
But since you decided to help me...
하지만 당신이 나를 돕기로 결정했기 때문에 ...
I must repay you.
나는 당신에게 갚아야합니다.
This is my fault.
이건 내 잘못이야.
I shouldn't have caught you.
난 당신을 잡지 말았어야 했어요.
Mr. Mu, the banquet is in the back.
뮤 씨, 연회는 뒤쪽에 있어요.
What are you doing here?
여기서 뭐하는거야?
If my father hadn't forced me...
아버지가 강요하지 않았다면...
I will not attend this banquet.
나는 이 연회에 참석하지 않을 것이다.
How much.
얼마나 많이.
I can't fit in...
난 어울리지 못해...
With people who follow the rules.
규칙을 따르는 사람들과 함께.
Why should I hang out with them?
내가 왜 그들과 어울려야 합니까 ?
Miss, if you still want to do it
아가씨 아직도 하고 싶으면
I will report this to your supervisor .
당신의 상사에게 보고하겠습니다 .
I'm serious.
진심이야.
Tuan.
투안.
Tuan...
투안...
you call me
당신은 나에게 전화
Park Jong-hoon is amazing.
박종훈 대단하네요.
Birds can also talk.
새들도 말을 할 수 있어요.
There's a snake behind you.
뒤에 뱀이 있어요.
Go now. Don't sit there.
지금 이동. 거기 앉지 마세요.
sideways. Or fly away.
옆으로. 아니면 날아가세요.
No. I might hurt that person.
아니요. 내가 그 사람을 다치게 할 수도 있어요.
wait!
기다리다!
Have we met before?
우리 전에 만난 적 있나요?
Just another woman Someone who tried to approach me.
그저 다른 여자 나에게 접근하려던 사람.
father...
아버지...
There are great jobs in this city.
이 도시에는 훌륭한 직업이 있습니다.
But you are ready to be my maid.
하지만 당신은 내 하녀가 될 준비가 되었습니다.
great.
좋아요.
Let's take a look at your skills.
당신의 실력을 살펴보겠습니다.
thank you
감사합니다.
Nanfeng, keep moving.
난펑, 계속 움직여.
All right.
알겠습니다.
All of this is caused by the Hua family.
이 모든 일은 Hua 가족에 의해 발생합니다 .
화첸.
화첸.
I swear One day I will expose your mistakes.
맹세합니다 언젠가는 당신의 실수를 폭로하겠습니다 .
Come this way. Put it here.
이리 오세요. 여기에 넣어.
On the chair.
의자에.
Put it home.
집에 넣어.
Just leave it here.
그냥 여기에 두세요.
Put it here.
여기에 넣어.
This is the purchase amount.
구매한 금액입니다.
I didn't buy it.
나는 그것을 사지 않았다.
This is my wedding gift.
이건 내 결혼 선물이에요.
I almost forgot.
나는 거의 잊었다.
Madam, today...
부인, 오늘은...
You can't sit still.
가만히 앉아있을 수는 없습니다.
why?
왜?
That woman named Myu...
뮤라는 그 여자...
so...
그래서...
Madam, you are here.
부인, 오셨습니다.
Kian.
키안.
Tuan.
투안.
What are they doing?
그들은 무엇을 하고 있나요?
Kian.
키안.
Our house is never empty because of work.
우리 집은 일 때문에 결코 비어 있지 않습니다.
I brought a maid.
나는 하녀를 데려왔다.
Look at this house full of people.
사람들로 가득한 이 집을 보세요 .
No need for another maid .
다른 가정부는 필요하지 않습니다 .
The other has no effect.
다른 하나는 아무 영향도 미치지 않습니다.
Eventually, she wants to become a maid.
결국, 그녀는 하녀가 되고 싶어합니다.
You don't need any more maids.
더 이상 하녀가 필요하지 않습니다 .
Last time I went to the reading room...
저번에 독서실에 갔을 때..
There aren't enough people there.
거기 사람이 부족해요.
Please let Mu Yao work there.
Mu Yao가 그곳에서 일하게 해주세요.
It's up to you.
당신한테 달렸습니다.
ma'am.
부인.
It's clear that he likes you.
그 사람이 당신을 좋아하는 게 분명해요.
I can't stand watching.
나는 보는 것을 참을 수 없다.
That's right, ma'am.
그렇죠, 부인.
Why don't you just agree and let him do it?
그냥 동의 하고 그 사람이 하게 놔두는 게 어때요?
Become a maid...
하녀가 되어라...
Then should I teach him?
그럼 내가 그 사람한테 가르쳐 줄까?
- Banxia. - Cik puan.
- Banxia. - Cik puan.
Let's take care of our hair.
머리를 손질하자.
Hello, madam. My name is Yixingxing.
안녕하세요, 부인. 저는 이싱싱이에요.
Mana Bansha?
마나 반샤?
Something happened to his family.
그의 가족에게 무슨 일이 일어났습니다 .
So he took a vacation.
그래서 그는 휴가를 냈습니다.
He will disappear for a while.
그는 잠시 동안 사라질 것입니다 .
Assistant Ji sent me here.
지 보조원이 나를 여기로 보냈습니다.
I am good at hairdressing and embroidery .
나는 미용과 자수를 잘한다 .
Okay, you do it.
좋아요, 당신이 하세요.
Sir, dessert is ready.
선생님, 디저트가 준비되었습니다.
wait for a sec.
잠깐만.
Sir, maybe the Queen could ask us...
선생님, 여왕님께서 우리에게 물어보실 수도 있겠네요...
If we come back late
우리가 늦게 돌아오면
Please wait a moment more.
잠시만 더 기다려 주세요.
Grandma won't be angry this time.
이번에는 할머니가 화내지 않을 거예요.
Tuan.
투안.
Teacher, please.
선생님, 제발요.
- Sir... - Who is he?
- 선생님... - 그는 누구죠?
- Teacher... - It seems like you like directing.
- 연출을 좋아하는 것 같군요.
- Teacher, don't you know him?
- 선생님... - 선생님, 그 사람 모르시나요?
Maid Hua's father...
메이드 후아의 아버지...
His younger sister is Mr. Zhong's wife.
그의 여동생은 종 씨의 아내입니다.
Now everyone is afraid of making him angry.
이제 모두가 그를 화나게 하는 것을 두려워합니다 .
Poor girl.
가난한 소녀.
- Look at. - Teacher, please.
- 바라보다. - 선생님, 부탁드립니다.
Dia culik Hua.
Dia culik Hua.
Sir, I cannot follow you.
선생님, 저는 당신을 따라갈 수 없습니다.
Teacher, please.
선생님, 부탁드립니다.
Sir, my father is waiting for me at home.
선생님, 아버지께서 집에서 저를 기다리고 계십니다.
I can't go back with you.
나는 당신과 함께 돌아갈 수 없습니다.
You should be proud.
당신은 자랑스러워해야합니다.
You are lucky because I chose you...
내가 당신을 선택했기 때문에 당신은 운이 좋은 것입니다 ...
To become our family.
우리 가족이 되려고.
road name.
도로.
- Sir... - Just go.
- 선생님... - 그냥 가세요.
How did Hwawon Ang raise a child like that?
화원앙은 어떻게 아이를 저렇게 키웠나...
To ruin the Zhong family's reputation?
Zhong 가족의 명성을 망치려고 ?
You usually work in secret.
당신은 보통 비밀리에 일합니다.
But please come downstairs and help the piper.
하지만 아래층으로 내려와서 파이프 연주자를 도와주세요.
Let's see how arrogant Hua Shen is...
Hua Shen이 얼마나 오만한지 보자 ...
And how bad he is.
그리고 그 사람이 얼마나 나쁜지.
All right.
알겠습니다.
I just want you to play for me.
나는 단지 당신이 나를 위해 놀아주기를 바랍니다.
What are you doing?
뭐하세요?
go away.
저리 가요.
Tuan.
투안.
We are in daylight and public places.
우리는 낮 과 공공 장소에 있습니다.
You shouldn't force him to do what you want .
당신이 원하는 것을 그에게 강요해서는 안됩니다 .
Who said I forced myself on him?
내가 그에게 강요했다고 누가 말했습니까?
i like him That is his blessing.
나는 그를 좋아한다. 그것이 그의 축복입니다.
That has nothing to do with you.
그거 너랑 상관 없어.
If you don't want to die, don't interfere.
죽고 싶지 않다면 방해하지 마세요.
We don't want to see others being bullied.
우리는 다른 사람들이 괴롭힘을 당하는 것을 보고 싶지 않습니다 .
So I think we'll participate.
그래서 우리가 참여할 것 같습니다.
Let's see if you can take him away from us.
당신이 그를 우리에게서 빼앗을 수 있는지 봅시다 .
You are looking for trouble.
당신은 문제를 찾고 있습니다.
Get rid of them!
그들을 제거하세요!
Teacher, my tooth fell out.
선생님, 이빨이 빠졌어요.
- Madam - Let's go.
- 부인 - 갑시다.
wake up.
깨우다.
You wait there.
너, 거기서 기다려.
Listen. I am Hua's only son...
들어보세요. 나는 Hua의 외아들입니다 ...
My sister is Mr. Jong’s wife.
제 여동생은 종 씨의 아내입니다.
So, I became Zhong Yeran’s brother-in-law!
그래서 나는 종예란의 처남이 되었습니다!
Apologize and get out of here...
사과하고 여기서 나가든지...
Lakaman Bonus
라카만 보너스
dickey.
작은 새.
I'm asking you to call me a girl...
내가 여자 좀 불러달라고 하네 ...
Do you want to play dice with your master?
주인님과 주사위 놀이를 하려고?
Roll the dice again!
다시 주사위를 던져라!
I'm bored
심심해요
I was locked up for 3 days...
3일 동안 갇혀 있었는데..
Now the sound of the dice is making me sick.
이제 주사위 소리가 메스꺼워지네요.
Can't you find me something new?
나에게 새로운 것을 찾아줄 수 없나요 ?
Assistant Hua and Mrs. Hua is out of town...
Hua 보좌관 과 Mrs. 후아는 도시 밖으로...
And I won't let you out.
그리고 당신을 내보내지 않을 것입니다.
Teacher, wait a minute.
선생님, 잠깐만요.
They will be back soon.
그들은 곧 돌아올 것이다.
sulfur.
황.
You remind me of something.
당신은 나 에게 뭔가를 생각나게 합니다.
Come this way.
이리 오세요.
That night I asked you...
그날 밤에 내가 너한테 물었지...
I went to Baekhwa Palace to invite a singer.
가수를 부르러 백화궁으로 갔습니다 .
You didn't bring the girl, you brought my father.
당신은 그 소녀를 데려온 것이 아니라 우리 아버지를 데려왔습니다.
you are brave
너는 용감하다.
You made me get punished.
당신은 내가 벌을 받게 만들었습니다.
Now I have been punished.
이제 나는 벌을 받았습니다.
Mr. Hwang, how are you going to make up for your mistakes?
황 씨, 실수를 어떻게 만회할 건가요?
Stop running. Stop.
달리기를 멈추세요. 멈추다.
Tuan.
투안.
Assistant Hua saw me leaving...
Hua 조수가 내가 나가는 걸 봤어...
And I don't dare hide the truth.
그리고 나는 감히 진실을 숨길 수 없습니다.
Don't you dare answer!
감히 대답하지 마세요!
I will beat you to death.
나는 당신을 때려 죽일 것입니다.
I was out of breath.
나는 숨이 막혔다.
Take a break.
쉬어 라.
Drink water.
물을 마셔보세요.
Let's see where we can run.
어디에서 달릴 수 있는지 봅시다 .
go away.
저리 가요.
Do you think you did something wrong?
당신이 뭔가 잘못했다고 생각합니까?
Yes, I was wrong. Please forgive.
네, 제가 잘못했어요. 용서 해줘.
I'm Boring. I'm so bored, Hwang!
나는 지루하다. 너무 심심해, 황!
Did you understand?
이해하셨나요?
I want to go out and have fun.
나가서 재미있게 놀고 싶어요.
But I am afraid of my father.
하지만 나는 아버지가 두렵습니다.
My father isn't home...
아버지는 집에 안 계시고..
My father is not at home.
아버지는 집에 없습니다.
I want to go out!
나 나가고 싶어!
Where are you going?
어디 가세요?
Assistant Hua said you are not allowed...
Hua 어시스턴트가 당신은 허용되지 않는다고 말했습니다...
Back to Baekhwa Palace.
다시 백화궁으로.
Who said I wanted to go there?
내가 거기에 가고 싶다고 누가 말했습니까?
I just want to go out and have some tea.
그냥 나가서 차를 마시고 싶어요.
Please don't do that! teacher!
제발 그러지 마세요! 선생님!